<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2021-12-12T17:07:08+01:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alche’s Blog</title><subtitle>I'm writing about stuff about what I have done.</subtitle><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">2022 Plans and Goals</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/productivity/2021/12/04/2022-plans-and-goals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Plans and Goals" /><published>2021-12-04T20:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-04T20:15:00+01:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/productivity/2021/12/04/2022-plans-and-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/productivity/2021/12/04/2022-plans-and-goals.html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to make my goals public this year. I believe that would force me to achieve them. Even though 1 person reads this blog, my brain will be in the &lt;em&gt;get shit done&lt;/em&gt; mode. Psychology is a weird thing. Even if I don’t finish everything I listed, It is ok. As Machiavelli said&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Acting in this like the skilful archer, who seeing that the object he would hit is distant, and knowing the range of his bow, takes aim much above the destined mark; not designing that his arrow should strike so high, but that flying high it may alight at the point intended.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I learn and have fun while doing so. I pretty much have same list for 3-4 years straight but I think this is the year I’ll say &lt;strong&gt;“This is Done!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-plans&quot;&gt;Project Plans&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nro2nsp-forwarder-in-the-nintendo-switch-itself&quot;&gt;NRO2NSP Forwarder in the Nintendo Switch Itself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wtf is that lumb of letters and number? If you don’t have a hacked switch they don’t make any sense but there is a commonly used tool that requires a Windows machine to set up. Essentially, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gbatemp.net/threads/nro2nsp-retroarch-rom-nro-forwarders.519915/&quot;&gt;NRO2NSP Forwarder&lt;/a&gt; is a home screen shortcuts for homebrew applications. While trying to setup my newly hacked switch, it generated a lot of headache for me and I decided to write this tool for switch itself. TLDR, It will be basic compiler for switch apps inside the Nintendo Switch itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3d-animation-generating-machine-learning-model&quot;&gt;3D Animation Generating Machine Learning Model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people unaware, I want to start a video game company for a long long time. I noticed that with small budgets, Indie game companies need to take loans against something to feed the team members. I tought I found a clever way to train a machine learning to design 3D Animations in bulk. Most probably, even if it creates nice animations, it will require human touch but I believe if a tool like this works it will cut a lot of cost and time. Little bit moonshot but I’m optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;finishing-my-3d-printer-kit-p3-steel&quot;&gt;Finishing my 3D Printer kit: P3 Steel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2018, I bought a 3D printer kit &lt;a href=&quot;https://reprap.org/wiki/P3Steel&quot;&gt;(Metal framed Prusa i3 MKI clone)&lt;/a&gt; for less than 100$. Even though the frame &lt;em&gt;etc.&lt;/em&gt; are very good, hardware was shit and it had a lot of missing electronics and cables. I decided to finish it and make it a proper workhorse with the electronics the frame work deserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;trackmania-driving-ai&quot;&gt;Trackmania Driving AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked on a shitty ML driving AI for race games for a while. It learned to go fast on my own weird game. I want to test it in a real racing game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-hyrib-kubernetes-cluster&quot;&gt;Building a Hyrib Kubernetes Cluster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have bunch of Raspberry Pis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/pi#:~:text=noun%20(1),plural%20pis%5C%20%CB%88p%C4%ABz%20%5C&quot;&gt;(That plural is WEIRD)&lt;/a&gt;. Essentially installing k3s and connecting it to the existing Kubernetes server I have. Seems easy, so I think it will not be a easy project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;obsidian-automatic-tag-and-relation-generator&quot;&gt;Obsidian Automatic Tag and Relation Generator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian is a note taking and organizing application.&lt;/a&gt; I want to create a tool for organizing my &lt;strong&gt;Obsidian Vault&lt;/strong&gt;. I use something I learned in university called &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;ocality &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;ensitive &lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;ashing. I think I can hack something together to detect some stuff for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stickerless-rubiks-connected&quot;&gt;Stickerless Rubik’s Connected&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rubiks.com/en-eu/connected-cube&quot;&gt;Rubik’s Connected&lt;/a&gt; is a smart cube that you can connect to your phone/computer for many different applications. But it has stickers and I don’t like stickers. I decided to 3d print replacement parts. I worked on this in 2021 for a very long time. It has some bugs but I believe I can get it working in 2022. Main problem is that very tiny 3d printed objects break very easily. I’ll ditch 100% 3d printed approach and will epoxy-cast the mechanically important parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basic-stream-element-clone&quot;&gt;Basic Stream Element Clone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://streamelements.com/&quot;&gt;Stream Elements&lt;/a&gt; seems a very easy product to re-implement, why there is no open source clones? BTW, fuck streamlabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning-goals&quot;&gt;Learning Goals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-how-to-drive&quot;&gt;Learn How to Drive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically I know how to drive but I have rusted over the years and Norwegian Governments asks me to re-learn everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-3000-norwegian-vocab&quot;&gt;Learn 3000 Norwegian Vocab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how I’m gonna measure this but I installed anki and duolingo, let’s see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-blender&quot;&gt;Learn Blender&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned I want to start a video game studio in near future. I have knowledge of how to program for video games, and I believe I’m a competent level designer. I suck at 3D Design. I decided to close that gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-nomad&quot;&gt;Learn Nomad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same goal as Blender but this is on iPad and uses brushes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;impossible-list-items&quot;&gt;Impossible List Items&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://impossiblehq.com/impossible-list/&quot;&gt;Insert Impossible List Explanation Here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;write-blog-post-every-week-for-a-year&quot;&gt;Write Blog post every week for a year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody reads my blog but I use it as a training ground for creative writing even thought my writing is not creative at all. I’ll work on this blog and my writing by practicing it every weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;upload-12-videos&quot;&gt;Upload 12 Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There several examples of long running project logs on Youtube that achieved success. For example Wintergatan and Randy the GG engine. I want to 2022 as my testing ground to build such a following that I can dedicate my work hours to such a work. I don’t think I will do that in 2022 but it is important to do it and learn in a small scale before I put in all of my chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stream-25-times&quot;&gt;Stream 25 Times&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think most of the things I’m doing daily can be streamed. I’m a lonely man, If I can stream and create a community while doing my daily activities, I would be very happy. I’ll try to do it but my hopes are not that high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading. Every quest worths less if you don’t tell me how you feel about this content! If you want to chat about a improvement I can do you please let me know at blog@thrideas.com&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="plans" /><summary type="html">I decided to make my goals public this year. I believe that would force me to achieve them. Even though 1 person reads this blog, my brain will be in the get shit done mode. Psychology is a weird thing. Even if I don’t finish everything I listed, It is ok. As Machiavelli said Acting in this like the skilful archer, who seeing that the object he would hit is distant, and knowing the range of his bow, takes aim much above the destined mark; not designing that his arrow should strike so high, but that flying high it may alight at the point intended.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Makeshift Home Server</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/28/a-makeshift-home-server.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Makeshift Home Server" /><published>2021-11-28T21:05:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-28T21:05:00+01:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/28/a-makeshift-home-server</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/28/a-makeshift-home-server.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things I’m annoyed at is that everyone has a very nice “Home Server Rack” with several 1U Servers and a 1U Network Switch. But I’m sure for every hi-end home server there is 2 makeshift home servers. I decided to share mine to show that you don’t need to have space for Rack mounted 2000-3000$ Home Server setup. You just need something that satisfies your home computation needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;base-machine&quot;&gt;Base Machine&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started using my 2014 Macbook Pro as the Home Server when my work provided me a new laptop in 2018. It served me nice but the poor laptop was struggling when I was trying to use it for anything. I re-installed MacOs and Docker to get started. I was only using plex and some minimal stuff so that setup was working quite nice. But the overhead of a graphical user interface and MacOs’s poor remote access features pushed me over the edge. I decided to convert everything to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alchemistake/my-home-kluster&quot;&gt;Linux and Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; since It is the easiest thing to manage for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-28-a-makeshift-home-server/ssd_converter.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;
I upgraded the internal storage to 1 TB. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B01CWWAENG/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;I bought one of NVMe to Macbook SSD converters&lt;/a&gt;, I poured bunch of time for research, more than necessary. You need to buy the correct converter for your own mac, most of the stuff online are garbage don’t take my choice as gospel. There are very detailed guides. They are not that good for daily use, &lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; they require re-flashing some chips &lt;em&gt;etc.&lt;/em&gt; But to use it on Linux and as a server I just needed to plug everything in and then puff it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;networking&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My laptop stays in a metal shelf and wifi signal is very poor. For a long time I used a USB wifi card with a long USB cable to it outside of the faraday cage of doom. But then I realized USB Wifi cards does not provide good enough connection speeds. &lt;a href=&quot;/home-server/2021/11/06/a-peculiar-case-of-a-home-networking.html&quot;&gt;So I installed a full fledged Wifi Router as the externel network card. I won’t go into details because I already wrote some stuff for that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;nas--harddisks&quot;&gt;NAS &amp;amp; Harddisks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-28-a-makeshift-home-server/hdd_cage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;
I decided to add more storage and add NAS Capability. I bought two of 5 Drive Cage for that. I shucked my external HDDs that I have laying around. I own too much external HDDs. I decided to use USB hubs I collected over the years to connect them to my Macbook. This is not a perfect solution at all but since my base machine is a Macbook this is one the only solutions I can use. It will not be the best but it will be at least good enough for my use case. I’m connecting to this device over Wifi so I can handle slower connection speeds on HDDs since wifi will be the bottleneck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-28-a-makeshift-home-server/smol_hdd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;
I had several smol HDDs from smol external HDDs. Rather than buying a 2.5 to 3.5 converter, I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:606950&quot;&gt;3D print this design&lt;/a&gt;. This design was very fast to print but after using them for a while I see that they are not eligible for the job. The print orientation and the placement of the 2.5 HDDs makes it impossible to stack them inside of the 5 Bay cage. I’ll redesign something very soon, but they are good enough now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a PSU for the all the HDDs I’m going to add. I was going to upgrade my desktop’s PSU so I decided to pull that upgrade little bit closer and used my old PSU and upgraded my computer’s PSU. I used a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aliexpress.com/item/4001358646207.html&quot;&gt;PSU power breakout board&lt;/a&gt; to have easy access to the different voltages. I’ll add a variable power converter to achive a 9V and 19.5V line in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sum-of-all-parts&quot;&gt;Sum of all Parts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-28-a-makeshift-home-server/sum_of_parts.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;
Since everything was loose parts around I decided to screw everything to a board I had from a broken Lack Table. I needed to shorted the board to make it fit inside of the shelving unit I have. It took around 5 Minutes. I hot glued the USB hub and Wifi Router. I used hot glue because it is strong enough to hold a USB hub and removable. I didn’t want to use hot glue for the Wifi Router but the wall mount holes were too small for any screw I had so I just used hot glue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To mount the HDD Cages I needed to drill big hole on top to pass the screw driver. It was not a big time waster. When that was ready I placed down a sheet of old bicycle inner tube I had since 2017 when I fucked up a bicycle ride. This will act like a vibration dampener. If you are still using bicycle inner tubes I suggest you hold on to the old ones. They are very handy insulator and elastic material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-28-a-makeshift-home-server/psu.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;
I didn’t want to use hot glue for everything though. Since everything that was mountable was mounted, I decided to use 3D Printed Brackets. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:1869903&quot;&gt;I used this ATX PSU Bracket&lt;/a&gt;. It is not the mechanically best part, but it was the fastest to print. I designed a simple L shape to hold the macbook in place. Thus most of the stuff were ready.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-28-a-makeshift-home-server/l_bracket.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything plugs in to a UPS I had since college that can handle up to 500W. If electricity goes out, I will hold everything up to 15 minutes. It is not a long time for UPS but It is a long time to detect Power Outage and shutdown everything safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;farewell&quot;&gt;Farewell!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is still not 100% Complete but I wanted to give a voice to the jank setups that exists. As you can notice most of the parts were stuff I already owned and repurposed, don’t hesitate to repurpose your old junk! In future, I’ll work on cable management and adding Raspberry Pis into the mix. Currently, I have problems with software more than hardware I think I’ll focus on that front more.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-28-a-makeshift-home-server/finale.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading. Every quest worths less if you don’t tell me how you feel about this content! If you want to chat about a improvement I can do you please let me know at blog@thrideas.com&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><category term="home-server" /><category term="hardware" /><summary type="html">One of the things I’m annoyed at is that everyone has a very nice “Home Server Rack” with several 1U Servers and a 1U Network Switch. But I’m sure for every hi-end home server there is 2 makeshift home servers. I decided to share mine to show that you don’t need to have space for Rack mounted 2000-3000$ Home Server setup. You just need something that satisfies your home computation needs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">50 Pages Review #2: How Luck Happens</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/2021/11/20/50-pages-review-2-how-luck-happens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="50 Pages Review #2: How Luck Happens" /><published>2021-11-20T16:16:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-20T16:16:00+01:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/2021/11/20/50-pages-review-2-how-luck-happens</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/2021/11/20/50-pages-review-2-how-luck-happens.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-20-50-pages-review-2-how-luck-happens/cover.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;New York Times bestselling author Janice Kaplan examines the phenomenon of luck–and discovers the exciting ways you can grab opportunities and make luck for yourself every day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;After spending a year researching and experiencing gratitude for The Gratitude Diaries, Janice Kaplan is back to tackle another big, mysterious influence in all our lives: luck. And this time she’s joined on her journey by coauthor Dr. Barnaby Marsh, a renowned academic who guides her exploration.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/35749437-how-luck-happens&quot;&gt;goodreads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-im-reading-this-book&quot;&gt;Why I’m reading this book?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last year, I have been using Blinkist free tier for discovering books I might like. This book caught my eyes or to be more correct my ears. I decided to give it a go to read the whole book. The book tries to explain the luck and what it is in layman’s terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;which-parts-ive-finished&quot;&gt;Which parts I’ve finished?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50 pages are exactly the first part and first three chapters. So in this preview, I’ll be spoiling the first chapter a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;did-i-learn-something-new&quot;&gt;Did I learn something new?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I didn’t learn something new but this book helped me put a new perspective on the stuff I already knew. The authors talk about luck in perspective to statistics and analytic data. Due to my college education and profession, I am exposed to those topics very much. But due to the classic case of horse blinders, it never occurred to me these informations can be applied to life directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;did-i-like-something&quot;&gt;Did I like something?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luck is a random event you won’t know when will it happen but you can prepare for these random events. If you are not prepared for &lt;strong&gt;the lucky event&lt;/strong&gt; you will miss your chances. &lt;em&gt;For example,&lt;/em&gt; if you are a musician, and you want someone to discover you. You should keep a copy of your work on you. If they are willing to give it a go, they will be able to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classic Wayne Gretzky quote: “You miss 100% of the shots you don’t take.”. Continuing with the musician example; you see someone can open the doors for you. If you don’t even ask for an audience from them, you won’t get discovered. It is not rude if you keep things respectful and don’t show down your work down somebody’s throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very generalized statistics are bullshit. When the statistics are generalized to a single number they don’t mean anything and they don’t apply to you at all. For example, 13% of people are obese. But there are almost millions of “input dimensions”, different factors that change the outcome. When you use only a single number then you are eliminating everything that provides some sort of information. If you want to weigh the possibility of something, you need to find the distribution on your input dimensions. For example, if you include family history, chronic diseases, etc. and just look at the distribution of obese people that fit your description the change might become 80% or 1%. The 13% does not mean anything to you. Nobody is average, everyone is unique. Try to use statistics that fit you better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other side of the coin of luck is &lt;strong&gt;risk&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are lucky you will achieve something, if you are not you will lose something. This is the basic explanation of taking risks. So taking risks is not always the biggest gain, biggest loss game. You can foresee somewhat accurate expected gain vs expected loss. So taking risks on low loss, big gain situations are the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes big gains are not even necessary. You can either spend your time on big results and a 1 in million chance or very frequent small gains. Which one will be more profitable for you is your call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;do-i-recommend-it&quot;&gt;Do I recommend it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend this book! The text of the book is not that science/statistics heavy, but they explain the concepts in an understandable manner and it is appliable to real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;will-i-continue-reading&quot;&gt;Will I continue Reading?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue reading it to the other cover. It is not that thick so I believe I can finish it very fast.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One of those weeks</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/14/one-of-those-weeks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One of those weeks" /><published>2021-11-14T17:46:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-14T17:46:00+01:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/14/one-of-those-weeks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/14/one-of-those-weeks.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m having one of those weeks. I was planning to finish my homeserver that has the parts sitting on the shelf and then wave of bad luck hit my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a small VLAN problem with my home server. My TV couldn’t find my plex server. Also I have a Wake On LAN server to start my computer from long distance in case I want to do something like download a game in advance or start a backup. The problem was &lt;a href=&quot;/home-server/2021/11/06/a-peculiar-case-of-a-home-networking.html&quot;&gt;the router setup I did last week&lt;/a&gt; was not sharing same LAN. So I wanted to setup a new networking with proper VLANs and dividing the network into purpose built VLANs like smart devices, server, home usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s where all started. I tested a lot of stuff they didn’t work as I intended then I decided to revert the settings changes and just have single shared pool of IPs which would solve the problem but wouldn’t give me granular access I wanted. No big deal, to be honest. Then fire nation attacked! Since both of the routers use OpenWRT they look identical. I accidentally installed the back up of the secondary router to the primary router which destroyed everything I worked. Plus, since configurations are drastically different the internet was gone for a while. Thankfully I had another router laying around at house so I quickly connected that while recovering the state of the both routers to work together. This whole failed operation took around 10 hours of my free time which de-railed my whole week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I couldn’t finish other parts of the server, thus parts are still in my shelf and sitting until I dedicate more time to do them. I hope It does not turn in to one of these weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent this problem happening again I installed a theme to main router I own thus they look different, you can find &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jerrykuku/luci-theme-argon&quot;&gt;the sexy theme I used here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jerrykuku/staff/master/argon2.gif&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This derailed everything for this week, I didn’t do the stuff I wanted to do but all is well. I learned a lot about OpenWRT, VLANs and networking.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><category term="home-server" /><category term="networking" /><summary type="html">I’m having one of those weeks. I was planning to finish my homeserver that has the parts sitting on the shelf and then wave of bad luck hit my project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A peculiar case of a home networking</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/06/a-peculiar-case-of-a-home-networking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A peculiar case of a home networking" /><published>2021-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/06/a-peculiar-case-of-a-home-networking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/home-server/2021/11/06/a-peculiar-case-of-a-home-networking.html">&lt;p&gt;I have a very unique and weird home server setup, I believe it will be interesting to tell about it. I’ll run through I have configured my server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my current house we have the internet port in the middle of the living room and I wanted to have the server in the small storage closet the other side of the house. Directly they are about 8 meters or so apart. Which can be done with an ethernet cable but due to sliding doors there is no way to route them without disabling the door from opening and closing. So I looked into getting powerline ethernet connections, I realized that there is multiple extension cords in between which reduces the effectiveness of these type of adapters. I decided to use a USB Wifi adapter to get some internet. I used this solution for a while then I realized using 2.4 GHz Wifi is slow for some of my use cases. For example, backing up my computer (~3TB) takes exteremely long and for some odd reason clogs all the other connections on my local network. Which prevents my wife from doing anything online. Rather than buying another and more powerful USB Wifi adapter, I decided to go with a cheapskate route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found an “AC1200” router which supports OpenWRT for little to none. OpenWRT (&lt;strong&gt;Open&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;b&gt;W&lt;/b&gt;ireless &lt;b&gt;R&lt;/b&gt;ou&lt;b&gt;T&lt;/b&gt;er) is an open source router operating system that unlocks a lot of features that router companies are lazy to enable. AC1200 stands for combined speed of Wifi 5 mode and Wifi 4 mode (867 + 300 ~= 1200 Mbps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openwrt.org/toh/netgear/r6120&quot;&gt;I installed OpenWRT following official OpenWRT tutorial.&lt;/a&gt; Then I set it up to connect to main router of my house using Wifi 5, Which will provide faster speed than both Wifi 4 and Powerline adapter. TLDR; I essentially bought another router and spend some time to convert it to a wifi adapter. This might seem overkill for now but let me justify myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/3d-printing/2021/10/10/ultimate-guide-to-octo4a.html&quot;&gt;I have Octo4a running on a phone&lt;/a&gt;. I want to isolate it from my main network to reduce security risks. So I set up Wifi 4 antenna to create a second Wifi SSID to just handle Octo4a and the smart power strip I use to power up/down my 3d printer. Also I wanted to have it connection to local area network even if power goes down. I added an uninterruptible power supply (UPS) for the router. Thus In case of emergency I can run a automation to make it safe when power comes back. 3D printers are dangerous devices I don’t want to start a fire by accident in the case of power surge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second reason: I have a plan to include all of my Raspberry Pies I own as a extension of the server to offload the work. Thus having a shared LAN interface will be very useful. I could’ve setup a LAN interface without a router but I’m lazy and this was the path of least resistance with maximum reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So If any of you want to hack me here is the diagram of the setup:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-06-a-peculiar-case-of-a-home-networking/diagram.png&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tested various different setups and it seems like this is the next best option compated to a physical cable. If you are not able to run a ethernet cable to somewhere it might be a good idea to use this 2 routers approach then. I hope this will help somebody!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><category term="home-server" /><category term="networking" /><summary type="html">I have a very unique and weird home server setup, I believe it will be interesting to tell about it. I’ll run through I have configured my server.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixing my game addiction</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/productivity/2021/11/05/fixing-my-game-addiction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixing my game addiction" /><published>2021-11-05T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-05T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/productivity/2021/11/05/fixing-my-game-addiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/productivity/2021/11/05/fixing-my-game-addiction.html">&lt;p&gt;I have a problem. I play too much Vidya Gaems. It is not a problem when I play a narative based single player game for fun but when I play something even remotely competitive I become a grustle focused Sigma. I can sink in 6-7 hours easily. Which turns my daily schedule upside down, and has a negative effect in my life. I’m playing until 2AM-3AM in the morning which makes me tired all day long. This gotta stop but I lack the willpower to not to do so. So I’ll delegate willpower to a computer program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my main concern is to have 60 minutes everyday to play. I can decrease or increase based on the circumstances. There is 4 options I considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;diy&quot;&gt;DIY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a feature of windows called “policy”. You can setup those to block some certain applications from running. With some basic scripting I would be able to do it. It is free but hard to setup. If you are cash stripped it can be done. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technipages.com/prevent-users-from-running-certain-programs&quot;&gt;You can continue your researche here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cold-turkey&quot;&gt;Cold Turkey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the defacto app blocker when you ask for an app blocker. Everyone knows it, everyone loves it. It has the time blocking power and it is called “allowance”. I didn’t buy it before because I believed it was a subscription based pricing. In my opinion, I find it very stupid to pay something only runs locally. It is 35$, I believe it is a honest price for an application you would use for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freedom&quot;&gt;Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom is the other best option. Has the functionality of the cold turkey and also provides syncing across devices. Since I’m not looking for a general app blocker I wasn’t interested in syncing across multiple devices. It has a subscription but In this case subscription is justified. If you get Yearly or Forever I believe it is a good value. Forever is too much expensive but it is equal to almost 5 years of yearly subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;others&quot;&gt;Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://alternativeto.net/&quot;&gt;Alternative to&lt;/a&gt; website there is nine gazillion blockers available. Most of them are on/off switches, which is okay if it is what you are looking. Some of them are just browser extensions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/leechblock-ng/blaaajhemilngeeffpbfkdjjoefldkok&quot;&gt;Leech Block&lt;/a&gt; is a nice option for a just browser blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;selection&quot;&gt;Selection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with Cold Turkey! Freedom and DIY options are nice but they have huge cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DIY option is free in respect to money but it would be a lot of time dedicated to get it working. And when It breaks down I need to fix it. I didn’t want to have a project, I needed a tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom is a nice option but I don’t need its extra bells and whistles. Thus it just becomes too expensive for my use case. If I want to unify my blocking softwares I think it worths the money on yearly account. I would test for a year and then buy the forever account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;setup&quot;&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I acquired the software I needed to setup my block settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-and-allowance-setup&quot;&gt;Time and Allowance Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up 00:00 to 00:00 block times in the weekdays and same hours for weekend. First block has 1 hour time allowance and the second block has 2 hours time allowance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-05-fixing-my-game-addiction/weekdays.png&quot; alt=&quot;Weekdays&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;Weekdays Setup&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-05-fixing-my-game-addiction/weekend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Weekend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;Weekend Setup&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blocking-apps-setup&quot;&gt;Blocking Apps Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cold Turkey allow two types of block detection, one is direct &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.exe&lt;/code&gt; files, other is detecting &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.exe&lt;/code&gt; files on a folder. I suggest folder detection because sometimes games and launchers launch different &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.exe&lt;/code&gt; files then the one you have launched. I disabled Epic Games Store, Steam and Uplay.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-05-fixing-my-game-addiction/apps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Weekend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problems&quot;&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a strange reason Uplay creates a lot of notifications when it get’s blocked. I think it might be just me having this problem but I think it can be solved by muting Cold Turkey notifications. Definitely Uplay is doing something problematic, it is not a Cold Turkey issue.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-11-05-fixing-my-game-addiction/notifications.png&quot; alt=&quot;Weekend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">I have a problem. I play too much Vidya Gaems. It is not a problem when I play a narative based single player game for fun but when I play something even remotely competitive I become a grustle focused Sigma. I can sink in 6-7 hours easily. Which turns my daily schedule upside down, and has a negative effect in my life. I’m playing until 2AM-3AM in the morning which makes me tired all day long. This gotta stop but I lack the willpower to not to do so. So I’ll delegate willpower to a computer program. Research So my main concern is to have 60 minutes everyday to play. I can decrease or increase based on the circumstances. There is 4 options I considered. DIY There is a feature of windows called “policy”. You can setup those to block some certain applications from running. With some basic scripting I would be able to do it. It is free but hard to setup. If you are cash stripped it can be done. You can continue your researche here. Cold Turkey This is the defacto app blocker when you ask for an app blocker. Everyone knows it, everyone loves it. It has the time blocking power and it is called “allowance”. I didn’t buy it before because I believed it was a subscription based pricing. In my opinion, I find it very stupid to pay something only runs locally. It is 35$, I believe it is a honest price for an application you would use for a very long time. Freedom Freedom is the other best option. Has the functionality of the cold turkey and also provides syncing across devices. Since I’m not looking for a general app blocker I wasn’t interested in syncing across multiple devices. It has a subscription but In this case subscription is justified. If you get Yearly or Forever I believe it is a good value. Forever is too much expensive but it is equal to almost 5 years of yearly subscription. Others If you go to Alternative to website there is nine gazillion blockers available. Most of them are on/off switches, which is okay if it is what you are looking. Some of them are just browser extensions. Leech Block is a nice option for a just browser blocking. Selection I decided to go with Cold Turkey! Freedom and DIY options are nice but they have huge cons. DIY option is free in respect to money but it would be a lot of time dedicated to get it working. And when It breaks down I need to fix it. I didn’t want to have a project, I needed a tool. Freedom is a nice option but I don’t need its extra bells and whistles. Thus it just becomes too expensive for my use case. If I want to unify my blocking softwares I think it worths the money on yearly account. I would test for a year and then buy the forever account. Setup After I acquired the software I needed to setup my block settings. Time and Allowance Setup I set up 00:00 to 00:00 block times in the weekdays and same hours for weekend. First block has 1 hour time allowance and the second block has 2 hours time allowance. Weekdays Setup Weekend Setup Blocking Apps Setup Cold Turkey allow two types of block detection, one is direct .exe files, other is detecting .exe files on a folder. I suggest folder detection because sometimes games and launchers launch different .exe files then the one you have launched. I disabled Epic Games Store, Steam and Uplay. Problems For a strange reason Uplay creates a lot of notifications when it get’s blocked. I think it might be just me having this problem but I think it can be solved by muting Cold Turkey notifications. Definitely Uplay is doing something problematic, it is not a Cold Turkey issue.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">50 Pages Review #1: Bullshit Jobs</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/books/2021/10/29/50-pages-review-1-bullshit-jobs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="50 Pages Review #1: Bullshit Jobs" /><published>2021-10-29T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/books/2021/10/29/50-pages-review-1-bullshit-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/books/2021/10/29/50-pages-review-1-bullshit-jobs.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-10-29-50-pages-review-1-bullshit-jobs/cover.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bullshit Jobs: A Theory&lt;/em&gt; is a 2018 book by anthropologist David Graeber that postulates the existence of meaningless jobs and analyzes their societal harm. He contends that over half of societal work is pointless, and becomes psychologically destructive when paired with a work ethic that associates work with self-worth.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullshit_Jobs&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across with the book a while back but I never had the time to read it. I have just finished my first 50 pages and I think it is time for a pause and evaluate the content of this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is a extension of a essay author had written back in 2013. I have known about this theory since the essay was out. Due to my prior experiences with workplaces and seeing many people with so called bullshit jobs, The essay resonated with me &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the book is not cutting it though. I didn’t like the repetitive nature of the book (at least in the first 50 pages). In the essay, it is more to the point and author explains the idea in very precise form. This quick and precises approach comes with the lack of evidence or convincing. In the book, author decides to take care of evidence and tries to be more convincing. He collected vast amount of data from the people who claim they have/had a bullshit job. He gives very many and varied anectodes to prove the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like this hurt the book in the short run. I decided to put down the book and not comeback. I was already sold to the idea and reading the book got boring very quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my final verdict, I suggest people to read &lt;a href=&quot;atlasofplaces.com/essays/on-the-phenomenon-of-bullshit-jobs/&quot;&gt;the essay&lt;/a&gt; first, then depending on the view point of yours the next steps vary. If you already agree with the essay you might skip the book but I heard the book has more content down the line like solutions to the this phenomenon. If you can’t stomach very repetitive parts, you can skip the first a few chapters to get the new points compared to the essay. If you don’t agree with the essay at all, go surf &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/antiwork/&quot;&gt;the anti-work subreddit&lt;/a&gt; to prime yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><category term="books" /><category term="50pages" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ultimate Guide to Octo4a</title><link href="https://alche.thrideas.com/3d-printing/2021/10/10/ultimate-guide-to-octo4a.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ultimate Guide to Octo4a" /><published>2021-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://alche.thrideas.com/3d-printing/2021/10/10/ultimate-guide-to-octo4a</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alche.thrideas.com/3d-printing/2021/10/10/ultimate-guide-to-octo4a.html">&lt;p&gt;The great person Gina Häußge created the Octoprint project, that allows you to control and monitor every aspect of your 3D printer and your printing jobs right from within your browser. People usually load it on a Raspberry Pi to use it but that is not the only way of using Octoprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an old android phone laying around somewhere, Octo4a can be free solution rather than buying a Raspberry Pi. This option requires some setup to get it work but it is not unlike Raspberry Pi option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide will show you how to setup your android device to act like a server for your 3D printer. It is not hard to install a few apps to get it working but I saw some people had questions and problems &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/octo4achat&quot;&gt;on the community&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll cover how to setup your device properly to make life easier and secure. I wont’ cover the hardware setup solution, It is very different from phone to phone but essentially you need to find a way to use any USB adapter and the charge at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start the setup, you should factory reset or install a custom rom from scratch to clean up your phone. Thus your phone will not use any extra resource to other applications left over from previous use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;octo4a-10&quot;&gt;Octo4a 1.0!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the official release of the Octo4a 1.0, everything has been changed! With new foundation new version is not compatible with direct update. If you are a old user of Octo4a, I strongly suggest you to backup the current installation before you start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/feelfreelinux/octo4a/releases&quot;&gt;Octo4a Github Page&lt;/a&gt; and download the latest release. If you never sideloaded an APK file before &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidauthority.com/how-to-install-apks-31494/&quot;&gt;you can follow this guide on Android Authority to learn&lt;/a&gt;. Long story short, you say OK or Yes when there is a prompt on screen. &lt;strong&gt;Quick security reminder: Don’t install any APKs you don’t trust.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After APK installation you need to install Octoprint. This is usually as straight forward as clicking a button! If anything weird happens try to uninstall the application and then re-install the APK and retry Octoprint installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are coming from an old installation, this is the time you use your backup. After restoring you need to change serial ports to include &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/dev/ttyOcto4a&lt;/code&gt; and clean the black list below.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-10-10-ultimate-guide-to-octo4a/port.png&quot; alt=&quot;Port Setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are brand new user, you can connect to octoprint UI with typing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makeuseof.com/tag/find-ip-address-mobile-smartphone/&quot;&gt;your phones ip&lt;/a&gt; followed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:5000&lt;/code&gt; into any browser. Example: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://192.168.1.255:5000/&lt;/code&gt;. You can follow the setup screen there to setup your device. If you are having problems finding the IP of your phone, you can use the browser on the phone you just setup. Just go to address &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://localhost:5000/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;camera-setup&quot;&gt;Camera Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should try out newly revamped built-in camera! It solved a lot of problems from previous Octo4a release. But due to the vast majority of different phones in the market, it sometimes has some problems or overheats the phone. I have a overheating problem due to my phone’s other hardware problem, so I like to use another 3rd part webcam solution. If you had any problems with built-in camera solution. I suggest using app called IP Webcam. You can install via &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pas.webcam&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt; or use a trusted APK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest these settings on IP Webcam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video Preferences/Video Resolution: 1280x720, 720p is enough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video Preferences/Focus Mode: Smooth, for recording video.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power Management/Stop Camera: Disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power Management/Deactivate Display: Enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power Management/Keep Screen Active: Disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power Management/Shallow Sleep: Enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power Management/Stream on Device Boot: Enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio Mode: Disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional Permissions/Allow Streaming in Background: Enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose to use a 3rd part Camera Application you need to update the camera settings on Octoprint UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-10-10-ultimate-guide-to-octo4a/webcam.png&quot; alt=&quot;Port Setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;out-of-home-access&quot;&gt;Out of Home Access&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to suggest ZeroTier for accessing your server when you are out of your home. This is a bit of a life style change but if you install ZeroTier to every device you own, you can securely access everything from everywhere. ZeroTier acts like a virtual LAN so your devices think you are connected to same modem essentially. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zerotier.com/download/&quot;&gt;You can go to ZeroTier Website to learn how to set it up.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now rather than using your phone’s local IP, you should use Zerotier IP of the phone. For example update the camera settings to use Zerotier IP. You can find out the IP via going inside the app and Clicking at the network name and the IP will be in the managed IP list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-10-10-ultimate-guide-to-octo4a/zerotier0.png&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-10-10-ultimate-guide-to-octo4a/zerotier1.png&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;remote-access-to-android&quot;&gt;Remote Access to Android&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an open source remote access app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bk138/droidVNC-NG&quot;&gt;Droid VNC-NG&lt;/a&gt;. If you install this app to your phone you don’t have to physical access to the phone anymore. You can connect with a VNC Client to control your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation and setting this application is very straight forward. You can go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bk138/droidVNC-NG&quot;&gt;Droid VNC-NG’s Github Page&lt;/a&gt; to download and install the APK. The app will walk you through the installation. You are pretty much done with this setup except one catch. You should enable double tap to wake up feature of your phone! Whenever you connect to your phone with this application you will connect to a black screen, since your phone is locked you need to be able to unlock it. Double tap solves this since you can send a double tap through DroidVNC-NG. You can enable this via Settings/Display/Tap to Wake: Enabled.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2021-10-10-ultimate-guide-to-octo4a/double_wake.png&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, You can use any VNC Client Application to access android portion of your setup to tweak in the future. I suggest VNC Viewer on Windows, iOS, Android and Remmina on Linux systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;file-server-to-android&quot;&gt;File Server to Android&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want send a new version of APK or install something new on the phone level you might want to have a easy way to send files over. FTP Server app will create a &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;ile &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;ransfer &lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;rotocol Server on your phone. Now you can use any FTP Client on your main devices. FileZilla is one of the most common FTP Client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get FTP Server on &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.xnano.android.ftpserver&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt; or use a Trusted APK file. There is very similar apps with very similar names. Whichever one works on your phone is fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;robust-backup-system&quot;&gt;Robust Backup System&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is forever. If your phone breaks down or something happens to octo4a files, it is hustle to set up a new instance from strach. Therefore everyone in earth needs to backup everything. There is a magical 2 step process that makes backups automatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Step: You should install this Octoprint plugin called &lt;a href=&quot;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/backupscheduler/&quot;&gt;Backup Scheduler&lt;/a&gt; This will backup your octoprint settings and plugins automatically to the your device. But saving to your device is not enough. You need to put your backups outside of the device itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second Step: There is this app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=dk.tacit.android.foldersync.lite&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US&quot;&gt;Folder Sync&lt;/a&gt; that I love! You can install and the follow instructions on the app to connect it to huge list of cloud storage providers. Then you can create a Folder pair to upload your backups to those could storage providers. Here is my settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sync type: to Remote Folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Local Folder: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/storage/emulated/0/Android/data/com.octo4a/files/.octoprint/data/backup&lt;/code&gt; This folder location might be different for you depending on where you installed your Octo4a app. Try to find a folder called &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/code&gt; and then follow the rest of the path from there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduled sync is enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule is every 12 hours. 24 is ok but I’m paranoid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I disabled notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rest of the setup is default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically you can install &lt;a href=&quot;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/googledrivebackup/&quot;&gt;Google Drive access directly inside the Octoprint&lt;/a&gt; but it required more setup and fiddling than installing the android application. If that version works and easier for you please notify me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;optional-tasker&quot;&gt;(Optional) Tasker&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to my phone being half fried, signals drops randomly. Thus whenever Wifi drops, I need to re-enable my Camera and ZeroTier apps all the time. To automate this part I installed Tasker to re-enable them automatically whenever they are disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve this I installed Tasker, IP Webcam Pro, and AutoInput. IP Webcam Pro has tasker integration so I can enable camera with that integration. AutoInput is used for opening ZeroTier App and flicking the enable disable button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people are insterested I can write another post about Tasker and how to set that up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;future-extensions&quot;&gt;Future Extensions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;klipper&quot;&gt;Klipper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never used klipper, so i didn’t tried to get it done. It seems like people are having some problems but I have 100% everything will iron out in short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-spagetti-detective&quot;&gt;The Spagetti Detective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to get TSD working. It didn’t I really don’t know why. But I don’t need it right now so I’m just calling it a day. I think the problem is with my TSD server so I will address that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;automized-deployment&quot;&gt;Automized Deployment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I have a high chance of my phone dying in a year or so and usually I’m lazy to setup everything manually. I believe I can cobble together a Ansible like program to install all the applications mentioned and even do the initial setup of them. I’m not doing it right now but wait until my phone breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading. Posts worth less if you don’t tell me how you feel about this content! If you want to chat about a improvement I can do you please let me know at blog@thrideas.com&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alchemistake</name><email>alchemistake@thrideas.com</email></author><category term="3d-printing" /><category term="octo4a" /><category term="octoprint" /><summary type="html">The great person Gina Häußge created the Octoprint project, that allows you to control and monitor every aspect of your 3D printer and your printing jobs right from within your browser. People usually load it on a Raspberry Pi to use it but that is not the only way of using Octoprint. If you have an old android phone laying around somewhere, Octo4a can be free solution rather than buying a Raspberry Pi. This option requires some setup to get it work but it is not unlike Raspberry Pi option. This guide will show you how to setup your android device to act like a server for your 3D printer. It is not hard to install a few apps to get it working but I saw some people had questions and problems on the community. I’ll cover how to setup your device properly to make life easier and secure. I wont’ cover the hardware setup solution, It is very different from phone to phone but essentially you need to find a way to use any USB adapter and the charge at the same time. Preparation To start the setup, you should factory reset or install a custom rom from scratch to clean up your phone. Thus your phone will not use any extra resource to other applications left over from previous use case. Octo4a 1.0! With the official release of the Octo4a 1.0, everything has been changed! With new foundation new version is not compatible with direct update. If you are a old user of Octo4a, I strongly suggest you to backup the current installation before you start. Go to Octo4a Github Page and download the latest release. If you never sideloaded an APK file before you can follow this guide on Android Authority to learn. Long story short, you say OK or Yes when there is a prompt on screen. Quick security reminder: Don’t install any APKs you don’t trust. After APK installation you need to install Octoprint. This is usually as straight forward as clicking a button! If anything weird happens try to uninstall the application and then re-install the APK and retry Octoprint installation. If you are coming from an old installation, this is the time you use your backup. After restoring you need to change serial ports to include /dev/ttyOcto4a and clean the black list below. If you are brand new user, you can connect to octoprint UI with typing your phones ip followed by :5000 into any browser. Example: http://192.168.1.255:5000/. You can follow the setup screen there to setup your device. If you are having problems finding the IP of your phone, you can use the browser on the phone you just setup. Just go to address http://localhost:5000/. Camera Setup You should try out newly revamped built-in camera! It solved a lot of problems from previous Octo4a release. But due to the vast majority of different phones in the market, it sometimes has some problems or overheats the phone. I have a overheating problem due to my phone’s other hardware problem, so I like to use another 3rd part webcam solution. If you had any problems with built-in camera solution. I suggest using app called IP Webcam. You can install via Google Play or use a trusted APK. I suggest these settings on IP Webcam. Video Preferences/Video Resolution: 1280x720, 720p is enough. Video Preferences/Focus Mode: Smooth, for recording video. Power Management/Stop Camera: Disabled. Power Management/Deactivate Display: Enabled. Power Management/Keep Screen Active: Disabled. Power Management/Shallow Sleep: Enabled. Power Management/Stream on Device Boot: Enabled. Audio Mode: Disabled. Optional Permissions/Allow Streaming in Background: Enabled. If you choose to use a 3rd part Camera Application you need to update the camera settings on Octoprint UI. Out of Home Access I’m going to suggest ZeroTier for accessing your server when you are out of your home. This is a bit of a life style change but if you install ZeroTier to every device you own, you can securely access everything from everywhere. ZeroTier acts like a virtual LAN so your devices think you are connected to same modem essentially. You can go to ZeroTier Website to learn how to set it up. Now rather than using your phone’s local IP, you should use Zerotier IP of the phone. For example update the camera settings to use Zerotier IP. You can find out the IP via going inside the app and Clicking at the network name and the IP will be in the managed IP list. Remote Access to Android There is an open source remote access app called Droid VNC-NG. If you install this app to your phone you don’t have to physical access to the phone anymore. You can connect with a VNC Client to control your phone. Installation and setting this application is very straight forward. You can go to Droid VNC-NG’s Github Page to download and install the APK. The app will walk you through the installation. You are pretty much done with this setup except one catch. You should enable double tap to wake up feature of your phone! Whenever you connect to your phone with this application you will connect to a black screen, since your phone is locked you need to be able to unlock it. Double tap solves this since you can send a double tap through DroidVNC-NG. You can enable this via Settings/Display/Tap to Wake: Enabled. Now, You can use any VNC Client Application to access android portion of your setup to tweak in the future. I suggest VNC Viewer on Windows, iOS, Android and Remmina on Linux systems. File Server to Android When you want send a new version of APK or install something new on the phone level you might want to have a easy way to send files over. FTP Server app will create a File Transfer Protocol Server on your phone. Now you can use any FTP Client on your main devices. FileZilla is one of the most common FTP Client. You can get FTP Server on Google Play or use a Trusted APK file. There is very similar apps with very similar names. Whichever one works on your phone is fine. Robust Backup System Nothing is forever. If your phone breaks down or something happens to octo4a files, it is hustle to set up a new instance from strach. Therefore everyone in earth needs to backup everything. There is a magical 2 step process that makes backups automatic. First Step: You should install this Octoprint plugin called Backup Scheduler This will backup your octoprint settings and plugins automatically to the your device. But saving to your device is not enough. You need to put your backups outside of the device itself. Second Step: There is this app called Folder Sync that I love! You can install and the follow instructions on the app to connect it to huge list of cloud storage providers. Then you can create a Folder pair to upload your backups to those could storage providers. Here is my settings: Sync type: to Remote Folder. Local Folder: /storage/emulated/0/Android/data/com.octo4a/files/.octoprint/data/backup This folder location might be different for you depending on where you installed your Octo4a app. Try to find a folder called Android and then follow the rest of the path from there. Scheduled sync is enabled. Schedule is every 12 hours. 24 is ok but I’m paranoid. I disabled notifications. Rest of the setup is default. Technically you can install Google Drive access directly inside the Octoprint but it required more setup and fiddling than installing the android application. If that version works and easier for you please notify me. (Optional) Tasker Due to my phone being half fried, signals drops randomly. Thus whenever Wifi drops, I need to re-enable my Camera and ZeroTier apps all the time. To automate this part I installed Tasker to re-enable them automatically whenever they are disconnected. To achieve this I installed Tasker, IP Webcam Pro, and AutoInput. IP Webcam Pro has tasker integration so I can enable camera with that integration. AutoInput is used for opening ZeroTier App and flicking the enable disable button. If people are insterested I can write another post about Tasker and how to set that up. Future Extensions Klipper I never used klipper, so i didn’t tried to get it done. It seems like people are having some problems but I have 100% everything will iron out in short time. The Spagetti Detective I tried to get TSD working. It didn’t I really don’t know why. But I don’t need it right now so I’m just calling it a day. I think the problem is with my TSD server so I will address that later. Automized Deployment. I think I have a high chance of my phone dying in a year or so and usually I’m lazy to setup everything manually. I believe I can cobble together a Ansible like program to install all the applications mentioned and even do the initial setup of them. I’m not doing it right now but wait until my phone breaks down. Feedback! Thank you for reading. Posts worth less if you don’t tell me how you feel about this content! If you want to chat about a improvement I can do you please let me know at blog@thrideas.com</summary></entry></feed>